<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yt - a tool for yaml</title>
    <link>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/</link>
    <description>Recent content on yt - a tool for yaml</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 15:58:49 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/posts/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 15:58:49 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/posts/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation I&amp;rsquo;ll create a release once I&amp;rsquo;m happy. Until then, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install go in order to install yt.
go get github.com/laher/yt  Run The default behaviour parses the input as YAML and spits it out in the same format.
Try running yt against the testdata/k8s.yaml file provided in this repository (it&amp;rsquo;s an anonymised kubernetes file, containing 3 yaml documents)
 yt &amp;lt; testdata/k8s.yaml  This is effectively the same as setting the main query to &#39;{{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 14:50:39 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>yt is a YAML processor in the spirit of jq and sed.
 yt can work with multi-document YAML files. yt is VERY experimental - please use with care.  Goals  Query yaml documents  Support multi-document files (with --- separator lines)  Manipulate yaml documents  Generate yaml Merge and combine yaml docs Keep yaml separate from looping / conditionals   Why Yaml seems to be everywhere at the moment, particularly in Ops tooling - see Kubernetes, Terraform, Concourse, Circle CI &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting Intro</title>
      <link>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/posts/scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 03:39:23 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.laher.net.nz/yt/posts/scripting/</guid>
      <description>yt uses the text/template package from Go&amp;rsquo;s standard library.
NOTE: although text/template is a templating language, and yt allows you to use it as such, the intention is more to use it as a scripting language. This allows your yaml to remain as valid yaml
For querying yaml, you won&amp;rsquo;t really need to understand Go templates in depth, but once you&amp;rsquo;re generating yaml, then it pays to understand the dialect&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>